Juan José Gouvêa Cardenas

junogouvea@gmail.com | +55 (92) 98480-4052 | linkedin/juanjosegouveac | Manaus, Brazil

About Me

Computer Engineering and Economics student with sense of leadership and entrepreneurial spirit. I aim to do useful things, share knowledge, spread positivity and inspire people. Experience leading teams, and working with intrapreneurship. Deeply interested in: Web3 Engineering and Cryptoeconomics.

Work Experiences

Contributing Writer Aug 2022 - Present

WEB3DEV

• Web3Dev is a DAO about web3 development. We are the largest community of web3 developers in Brazil, generating free and quality educational content. I perform translation (from English to Portuguese), review and produce articles on content related to web3, blockchain, DAO's, cryptoassets, NFT's, and more.

Innovation Intern Mar 2022 - Present

ECOA PUCRIO

- Internship in research and creative development for the insurance industry. Insurtech Innovation Program is a partnership between LES (Laboratório de Engenharia de Software at PUC-Rio), IRB Brasil RE and Mongeral Aegon, where interns have the chance to show off their entrepreneurial and creative skills in order to develop smart solutions that benefit the insurance industry.
- Along this journey I have, together with my team, developed solutions to challenges, making use of emerging technologies and ingenuity.

Education

Centro Universitário do Norte (UniNorte)

Jun 2021 - Present

Undergraduate, Economics.

Centro Universitário Fametro (Fametro)

Jan 2020 - Present

Undergraduate, Computer Engineering.

Courses

- Fundamentos de TI: Hardware e Software, by Fundação Bradesco in Jul 2021.
- Projetos de Sistemas de TI, by Fundação Bradesco in Aug 2021.
- Basics of Blockchain with Python, by Codecademy in Jan 2022.

Volunteer Experiences

Community Contributor

Aug 2022 - Present

WEB3DEV

• Translating Web3, blockchain, descentralized apps, DAOs, crypto and tokens, and other related content into Brazilian Portuguese. Creating articles in a variety of Web3 subjects.

Open Source Translator

Jun 2022 - Present

Ethereum

• I'm currently volunteering as an open source translator at ethereum.org, helping bringing Ethereum to the Latin-American community, and making the platform more accessible. The Ethereum Translation Program is a collaborative effort to translate ethereum.org into different languages in order to make the website more accessible to billions of non-English speakers around the world.

Projects

Plethora Hub May 2021 - Present

• Plethora Hub is a Web3, Crypto, DeFi, NFT, Blockchain, Metaverse and financial wisdom portal, in which everyday, news and related content is sent.

Honors & Awards

- [Interregional Phase] 2° Place, MinTIC Colciencias, One of the winners of the Science and Technology fair of the Ministry of Information and Communication Technologies of Colombia (MinTIC), held by COLCIENCIAS in Sep 2015.
- [Department of Amazonas, Colombia] 1° Place, MinTIC Colciencias, Research Group in Education and Technology, TECNONAVAL. First place at the Science and Technology fair of the Ministry of Information and Communication Technologies of Colombia (MinTIC), held by COLCIENCIAS in Sep 2014.

Extras

Soft Skills

Leadership, Teams Management, Time Management, Team Work, Communication.

Tools

Figma, Miro, Notion, Clickup, Discord, VS Code.

Languages

- English (Advanced)
- · Spanish (Native)
- · Portuguese (Native)